Finding Aid for Laird Bell papers, 1903-1962
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Laird Bell papers 1903-1962
Bell, Laird, 1883-1965.
1 linear foot
8568 Aa 2
Chicago attorney; correspondence, speeches, articles, and subject files relating to his public career.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Margaret Cameron (donor no. 2688 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Laird Bell was born in Winona, Minnesota on April 6, 1883. He received his B.A. from Harvard in 1904 and his J.D. from the University of Chicago in 1907. Upon admission to the bar, he commenced the practice of law in Chicago. Bell, throughout his career, was active in various educational organizations, serving, for example, as chairman of the board of trustees of the University of Chicago (1949-1953), chairman of the board of trustees of Carleton College (1943-1955), and member of the board of overseers at Harvard (1948-1954).
Laird Bell was also involved in public service organizations. In 1955, he was alternate U. S. delegate to 10th Assembly of the United Nations. He died October 21, 1965.
The Laird Bell collection consists of a single series of Personal and Professional papers. Included are speeches, articles, written, and subject files pertaining to his various organizational activities, especially his work as alternate U. S. delegate to 10th Assembly of the United Nations in 1955. There are also various material pertaining to the life of his grandfather, Wisconsin lumberman, W. H. Laird.
Subjects:
Universities and colleges--United States.; Education--United States.; Germany.; Laird, W. H.; Logging--United States.; Lumbering--United States.; United Nations.; United States. Timber Conservation Board.
- Personal and Professional Papers
  - Papers re. research and writing of biography of grandfather, W. H. Laird (Box 1)
  - Papers, 1955-1963 re. service as alternate delegate to 10th Assembly, United Nations (1955-1956) and later interest in the United Nations (Box 1)
  - Papers re. Fund for the Republic (Box 1)
  - Papers, 1931-1934 re. U.S. Timber Conservation Board (particularly concerning timber conservation) (Box 1)
  - Speeches and articles, 1903-1962 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1936-1954 (largely concerning speeches and articles) (Box 1)
  - Correspondence re. Atlantic articles, "Admit and Flunk" (Box 1)
  - Transcripts of letters, 1918-1919 and 1934 describing work in France, the Germany economy, etc. (Box 1)
  - Newspaper clippings and miscellanea (Box 1)
  - The Educations of Laird Bell, by Erling Larson (Box 1)